<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="wlr_layer_shell_unstable_v1">
  <copyright>
    Copyright © 2017 Drew DeVault

    Permission to use, copy, modify, distribute, and sell this
    software and its documentation for any purpose is hereby granted
    without fee, provided that the above copyright notice appear in
    all copies and that both that copyright notice and this permission
    notice appear in supporting documentation, and that the name of
    the copyright holders not be used in advertising or publicity
    pertaining to distribution of the software without specific,
    written prior permission.  The copyright holders make no
    representations about the suitability of this software for any
    purpose.  It is provided "as is" without express or implied
    warranty.

    THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES WITH REGARD TO THIS
    SOFTWARE, INCLUDING ALL IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND
    FITNESS, IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY
    SPECIAL, INDIRECT OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR ANY DAMAGES
    WHATSOEVER RESULTING FROM LOSS OF USE, DATA OR PROFITS, WHETHER IN
    AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, NEGLIGENCE OR OTHER TORTIOUS ACTION,
    ARISING OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE USE OR PERFORMANCE OF
    THIS SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>

  <interface name="zwlr_layer_shell_v1" version="4">
    <description summary="create surfaces that are layers of the desktop">
      Clients can use this interface to assign the surface_layer role to
      wl_surfaces. Such surfaces are displayed between the background and
      applications.
    </description>

    <request name="get_layer_surface">
      <description summary="create a layer_surface from a surface">
        Create a layer surface for an existing surface. This assigns the role
        of layer_surface, or raises a protocol error if another role is already
        assigned.
      </description>
      <arg name="id" type="new_id" interface="zwlr_layer_surface_v1"/>
      <arg name="surface" type="object" interface="wl_surface"/>
      <arg name="output" type="object" interface="wl_output" allow-null="true"
           summary="Restrict to a specific output, or NULL to use default"/>
      <arg name="layer" type="uint" enum="layer" summary="Layer to add this surface to"/>
      <arg name="namespace" type="string" summary="Namespace for the layer surface"/>
    </request>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor" since="3">
      <description summary="destroy the layer_shell object">
        This request indicates that the client will not use the layer_shell
        object any more. Objects that have been created through this instance
        are not affected.
      </description>
    </request>

    <enum name="error">
      <entry name="role"                       value="0" summary="wl_surface has another role"/>
      <entry name="invalid_layer"              value="1" summary="layer value is invalid"/>
      <entry name="already_constructed"        value="2" summary="wl_surface has a buffer attached or committed"/>
      <entry name="invalid_surface_state"      value="3" since="4"/>
      <entry name="invalid_size"               value="4" since="4"/>
      <entry name="invalid_anchor"             value="5" since="4"/>
      <entry name="invalid_keyboard_interactivity" value="6" since="4"/>
      <entry name="invalid_exclusive_edge"     value="7" since="4"/>
    </enum>

    <enum name="layer">
      <description summary="available layers for surfaces">
        These values indicate which layers a surface can be rendered to. They
        are ordered by z depth, bottom-most first. Traditional shell surfaces
        will typically be rendered between the bottom and top layers.
        Fullscreen shell surfaces are typically rendered at the top layer.
        Multiple surfaces can share a single layer, and the ordering within a
        single layer is undefined.
      </description>
      <entry name="background" value="0"/>
      <entry name="bottom"     value="1"/>
      <entry name="top"        value="2"/>
      <entry name="overlay"    value="3"/>
    </enum>
  </interface>

  <interface name="zwlr_layer_surface_v1" version="4">
    <description summary="layer metadata interface">
      An interface that may be implemented by a wl_surface, for surfaces that
      are designed to be rendered as a layer of a stacked desktop-like
      environment.
    </description>

    <request name="set_size">
      <description summary="sets the size of the surface">
        Sets the size of the surface in surface-local coordinates. The
        compositor will display the surface centered with respect to its
        anchors.

        If you pass 0 for either value, the compositor will assign it and
        inform you of the assignment in the configure event. You must set your
        anchor to opposite edges in the axis the compositor assigns. If you do
        not, the compositor will trap you with an invalid_size error. When the
        width or height is 0 and the corresponding horizontal or vertical
        anchors are set, or when a corresponding anchor is not set, the
        compositor treats this as a hint to expand the surface.
      </description>
      <arg name="width"  type="uint"/>
      <arg name="height" type="uint"/>
    </request>

    <request name="set_anchor">
      <description summary="configures the anchor point of the surface">
        Requests that the compositor anchor the surface to the specified edges
        and corners. If two orthogonal edges are specified, e.g. 'top' and
        'left', the anchor point will be the top left corner of the output;
        otherwise, the anchor point will be centered on that edge, or the
        center if none is specified.
      </description>
      <arg name="anchor" type="uint" enum="anchor"/>
    </request>

    <request name="set_exclusive_zone">
      <description summary="configures the exclusive geometry of this surface">
        Requests that the compositor avoids occluding an area with other
        surfaces. The compositor's use of this information is
        implementation-dependent - do not assume that this region will be
        vacant from other surfaces.

        A value of -1 indicates that the surface does not wish to be moved to
        accommodate for other surfaces, and the compositor should extend it to
        the edges of the output, ignoring the position set by set_margin.
      </description>
      <arg name="zone" type="int"/>
    </request>

    <request name="set_margin">
      <description summary="sets a margin from the anchor point">
        Requests that the surface be placed some distance away from the anchor
        point on the output, in surface-local coordinates. Setting this value
        for edges you are not anchored to has no effect.
      </description>
      <arg name="top"    type="int"/>
      <arg name="right"  type="int"/>
      <arg name="bottom" type="int"/>
      <arg name="left"   type="int"/>
    </request>

    <request name="set_keyboard_interactivity">
      <description summary="requests keyboard events">
        Set how keyboard events are delivered to this surface. By default,
        layer shell surfaces do not receive keyboard events; this request can
        be used to change this.
      </description>
      <arg name="keyboard_interactivity" type="uint"
           enum="keyboard_interactivity"/>
    </request>

    <request name="get_popup">
      <description summary="assign this layer_surface as an xdg_popup parent">
        This assigns an xdg_popup's parent to this layer_surface. This popup
        should have been created via xdg_surface::get_popup with the parent set
        to NULL, and this request must be invoked before committing the popup's
        initial state.
      </description>
      <arg name="popup" type="object" interface="xdg_popup"/>
    </request>

    <request name="ack_configure">
      <description summary="ack a configure event">
        When a configure event is received, if a client does not need to change
        the state of the surface in response to the configure event, then the
        client must nonetheless send an ack_configure request before committing
        a new surface.
      </description>
      <arg name="serial" type="uint" summary="the serial from the configure event"/>
    </request>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroy the layer_surface">
        This request destroys the layer surface.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="set_layer" since="2">
      <description summary="change the layer of the surface">
        Change the layer that the surface is rendered on. Layer is specified by
        the corresponding value in the zwlr_layer_shell_v1 enum.
      </description>
      <arg name="layer" type="uint" enum="zwlr_layer_shell_v1.layer"
           summary="layer to move this surface to"/>
    </request>

    <request name="set_exclusive_edge" since="4">
      <description summary="set the edge the exclusive zone will be applied to">
        Requests an edge for the exclusive zone to apply. The exclusive edge
        will be automatically deduced from anchor points when possible, but
        when two orthogonal edges are anchored, the result is ambiguous and
        the compositor would be expected to set the exclusive zone to 0.
        This request solves that ambiguity.
      </description>
      <arg name="edge" type="uint" enum="anchor"/>
    </request>

    <event name="configure">
      <description summary="suggest a surface change">
        The configure event asks the client to resize its surface.
      </description>
      <arg name="serial" type="uint"/>
      <arg name="width"  type="uint"/>
      <arg name="height" type="uint"/>
    </event>

    <event name="closed">
      <description summary="surface should be closed">
        The closed event is sent by the compositor when the surface will no
        longer be shown. The output may have been destroyed or the user may
        have asked for it to be removed. Further changes to the surface will
        be ignored. The client should destroy the resource after receiving
        this event, and create a new surface if they so choose.
      </description>
    </event>

    <enum name="keyboard_interactivity">
      <description summary="types of keyboard interaction possible for a layer shell surface">
        Types of keyboard interaction possible for layer shell surfaces. The
        rationale for this is that some surfaces (cursors, tooltips) should
        not be able to receive keyboard focus while others (a lock screen)
        should always have such focus.
      </description>
      <entry name="none"      value="0" summary="no keyboard focus is possible"/>
      <entry name="exclusive" value="1"
             summary="request exclusive keyboard focus if this surface is above the shell surface layer"/>
      <entry name="on_demand" value="2" since="4"
             summary="this surface can be focused and unfocused by the user"/>
    </enum>

    <enum name="anchor" bitfield="true">
      <entry name="top"    value="1" summary="the top edge of the anchor rectangle"/>
      <entry name="bottom" value="2" summary="the bottom edge of the anchor rectangle"/>
      <entry name="left"   value="4" summary="the left edge of the anchor rectangle"/>
      <entry name="right"  value="8" summary="the right edge of the anchor rectangle"/>
    </enum>
  </interface>
</protocol>
